在拉丁美洲每60分钟即发生 一起绑架案件
70%的受害者无法生还
火线救援
- 是 请讲 - 家人最重要
- Si. Bueno. - Family is everything.
不是吗?
No?
你爱你的儿子吗?
Now, do you love your son?
是
Si.
现在 明白吗?
Now do you understand?
你有1000万的保单 我知道
You have a $ 10 million insurance policy. I know that.
按以下指示去做
否则让你孩子去见上帝
脱下你的衬衣
将它伸出窗外以鉴别该车
专业点
单独来
艾帕索 得克萨斯
美国/墨西哥边界
隆吉娜!
Georgina!
听我的 我会爱你 快点
Obey me, I will loveyou. Come on.
这真的管用?
That's how it works, huh?
- 简单 - 说的没错
- Simple. - That's right.
来
Mwah.
她有妹妹吗?
She got a sister?
生意好吗?
How's business?
日本人 做得很大
The Japanese are here in a big way.
劳动力低廉 厂房又大
Cheap labor, factory space.
但他们觉得在艾帕索边境 那边要安全得多
But they feel a lot safer living over the border in El Paso.
我把他们接来送去的 他们把我当约翰・韦恩了
I ferry them back and forth. They think I'm John Wayne.
- 啊 - 来吧
- Ah. - Come on.
- 我在这里就像个国王 - 是 没错
- I live like a king down here. - Yes, you do.
- 现在有工作吗? - 有 没
- You been workin'? - Yeah. No.
没 一直都游手好闲的
Nah. Been movin' around, you know.
去了哥伦比亚和几个无名小地 没事能提起我兴趣
Colombia, couple of places I can't name. Nothing catches my fancy.
哦
Oh.
你认为上帝会宽恕我们做的事吗?
You think God will forgive us forwhat we've done?
- 不会 - 不会吗?
- No. - You don't?
我也这么想
Me either.
- 打算住多久? - 不知道 我只是
- How long you staying? - I don't know. I just you know.
来看看你 雷 看看你还好吗
I wanted to see you, Ray, see how you're doin'.
一冲动就来了
You know, I came by on impulse.
我冲动了可会做点别的
Well, I could do with some impulse.
怎么了?
What happened?
家里付了赎金
Family paid the ransom
他们几天后就放了小孩回家
then they sent the kid home after a couple of days
当然是少了一只耳朵
minus an ear, of course.
现在墨西哥城有钱的母亲 都想请个好一点的保镖
Now every mother in Mexico City with a little bit of moneywants bigger and better bodyguards
我太太也想雇
my own wife included.
我真想反驳你 但她做得对 她做得对
I hate to break it to you, but she's right. She's right.
听着 山米 我的所有客户 都有被绑勒索的保险
Look, Sammy, all my clients have, uh, kidnap and ransom insurance.
我有保单 美商公司 我父亲给的
I have a policy. A.I.G. My dad gave it to me.
是 我知道 我帮你父亲保的
Yeah, I know. I got it for your dad.
但你若不续保60天后怎么办?
But what are you gonna do in 60 days whenyou can't renew it?
- 这样不行 因为你没保镖 - 我知道 但我得让艾美里欧走
- You can't because you don't have a bodyguard. - I had to let Emilio go.
你得让莉莎开心 我是说 那样才算是个好丈夫
You gotta please Lisa. I mean, hey, ass like that's hard to find.
听着 保镖就像其它东西一样
Look, a bodyguard's like anything else.
一分价钱一分货
You get whatyou pay for, okay?
你做得到 能找个有经验的保镖
You could do this. You get one that's got a decent resume.
我们又不找什么超人 对吧?
We're not looking for goddamn Superman here, right?
更新保单前找个便宜点的
Get someone cheap till you renew the policy
然后换掉那个不中用的人
and then, uh then fire the prick forwhatever. Incompetence.
言归正传 最重要的是 你女儿能回去上学
All kidding aside, the most important thing is thatyour daughter goes back to school
你太太也不用担心害怕
and thatyourwife gets to save face.
那样你一家就不会是唯一 小区内未受保护的人家
This way, you won't be the only unprotected family in the neighborhood.
没错 当保镖 你的西班牙语够了
That's right. A bodyguard. YourSpanish is good enough.
- 你疯了 - 想想好的一面
- You're crazy. - You even look the part.
凭我这状态 连死人都保护不了
I n my state, I couldn't guard a corpse.
是露财炫耀的有钱人 都是做给人看的
It's rich guys flashing their cash. It's all forshow.
- 不会有事的 - 是吗? 他们会雇老酒鬼吗?
- Nothing's gonna happen. - Yeah? You think they'd hire a drunk, a has- been?
你得自我克制一下
You have to keep it under control.
如果真有绑架 我该怎么办?
What if there was, you know, say, a kidnapping attempt? What do I do then?
尽力而为 人家付钱就是要你做得出色
You do your best. They're not gonna be payingyou enough to perform miracles.
- 不知道 - 也不是要你骗钱 克雷塞
- I don't know. - It's not exactly a scam, Crease.
- 使出你一半力气就足够了 - 是啊
- Even at half speed, you're pretty damn good. - Yeah.
保镖必须得贴身护人
Bodyguard's gotta be close to people though.
而且还得不停地说话 你知道这个我不在行
He gotta talk all the time, and I'm no good at that.
你是沉默型的 人家会感激的
You'll be the silent type. People are gonna appreciate that.
当保镖 雇主是谁?
Bodyguard. So who's the guy?
山默尔・拉莫斯 是个年轻人
Samuel Ramos. He's a young guy.
他在华瑞兹有家工厂
He owns one ofthe plants inJuarez.
是吗?
Yeah?
日本车产业不景气
The Jap car industry is in the toilet.
他想说服福特跟他合作
He's trying to persuade Ford to partnerwith him.
我想他有麻烦 他家人住在墨西哥城
I think he's in trouble. His family lives in Mexico City.
他问我是否有可以相信的人
He asked me if l knew anybody he could trust.
- 你就想到了我 - 是
- And you thought of me. - Yeah.
做点工作 克雷塞 调节一下
Take a job, Crease. Breathe some air.
然后再决定去留
Then decide if you want to stick around or not.
而且我也能来看你 这里我找不到人说话
Besides, I'm glad to see you. I got nobody to talk to down here.
听着 我太太要请的是 懂规矩有礼貌的人
Listen, my wife wants someone presentable and polite.
你是她这星期接见的第五个人
You'll be the fifth candidate she sees this week.
你的履历真令人印象深刻
Your resume's quite impressive.
16年丰富的反恐作战从军经验
Sixteen years of military experience, extensive counterterrorism work.
恐怕不是人人都请得起你 要价多少?
I'm surprised anybody could afford you. What's the catch?
我喝酒
I drink.
有何影响?
How does that affect you?
嗯
Well
同等反应时间
coordination, reaction time.
若有职业绑匪绑架你女儿 我会尽力救她
If top professionals try to kidnap your daughter, I'll do the best I can
但这得另外算钱
but the service will be on parwith the pay.
要是业余绑匪呢?
What ifamateurs tried?
也许我会杀了他们 可能吗?
I'd probably kill 'em. Is that likely?
不
No.
没人会知道你喝酒 包括我太太
No one is to know aboutyour drinking. That includes mywife.
莉莎!
Lisa!
我太太莉莎 这位是约翰 克雷塞
My wife, Lisa. And this is John Creasy.
- 你是美国人 - 你也是
- You're an American. - So are you.
都在这里了
It's all in there.
想喝点什么吗?
Would you like a drink?
好的 杰克酒加水
Yes, uh,Jack and water'd be good.
- 以前做过这种工作吗? - 没 太太
- Haveyou done much ofthis kindofwork before? - No, ma'am.
但他有丰富的救援经验
But he has a lot of experience in related fields.
- 成家了吗 克雷塞先生? - 没
- You have a family, Mr. Creasy? - No.
苹塔
Pita.
- 谢谢 - 是的 妈妈?
- Thankyou. - Yes, Mom?
宝贝 这位是克雷塞先生
Honey, this is, uh, Mr. Creasy.
你好吗? 克雷塞先生
很高兴见到你
说英语 宝贝
In English, honey.
能带克雷塞先生去看房间吗?
Um, do you wanna show Mr. Creasy to his room?
- 跟我来 克雷塞先生 - 好的
- This way, Mr. Creasy. - Okay.
谢谢
Thankyou.
就这样?
Just like that?
我认为他很适合
I think it's nice
他是个美国人
that he's an American.
我认为他棒极了 确定吗?
I think it's terrific. You sure?
谢谢
Thankyou.
感觉好极了
I feel better now.
- 你好 布鲁诺 - 午安
- !Hola, Bruno!- !Buenas tardes!
那是布鲁诺 花匠
That's Bruno, the gardener.
那是玛丽亚 厨子
And, um, that's Maria, the cook.
- 你好 玛丽亚 - 你好 苹塔
- !Hola, Maria! - Hola, Pita.
我们两星期前刚整理过房间 比以前要漂亮
We fixed the room up two weeks ago. It's nicer than before.
这里有电视和CD播放机 你喜欢哪种音乐 克雷塞先生?
You've got a TV and C.D. player. What kind ofmusic do you like, Mr. Creasy?
不知道
I don't know.
- 不知道? - 不知道
- You don't know? - I don't know.
那是小鸟
That's Bird.
艾美里欧走时忘了带
Emilio forgot to take him when he left.
艾美里欧是我上一任保镖
Emilio was my last bodyguard.
以前保护过很多孩子吗 克雷塞先生?
Have you protected a lot of children before, Mr. Creasy?
克雷塞 你叫我克雷塞 没有 你就是第一个
Creasy. You can call me Creasy. And no, you're the first.
克雷塞
Creasy.
再见 克雷塞
Bye, Creasy.
再见
So long.
再见 小鸟
Bye, Bird.
噢
Ow.
- 明天要上学了 - 就是说我们能有只狗了?
- School tomorrow, peeps. - Does that mean we can get a dog?
爸爸答应过我回学校就给买
Dad promised me one when I went back to school.
是 看看吧
Yeah, we'll see.
如果给你狗 你会不要小熊吗?
If you get a dog, will you give up your bear?
你大了 别再玩小熊了
You're getting too old for him.
- 喜欢克雷塞先生吗? - 克雷塞
- How'd you like Mr. Creasy? - Creasy.
他说就叫他克雷塞
He said to call him just Creasy.
- 不行 - 那样不尊重吗?
- Uh- huh. - That isn't disrespectful, is it?
不尊重 除非他要你叫
No, not if he asked you.
行了 睡吧
Here. There you go.
- 他也像只熊 - 是吗?
- He's like a bear too. - Yeah?
伤心的大熊熊
A big, sad bear.
- 他伤心吗? - 我想是这么的
- Is he sad? - I think. Or something.
- 晚安 宝贝 - 晚安
- Good night, honey. - Night.
- 早上能给我点棉花糖吗? - 棉花糖?
- Oh, can you get me some floss in the morning? - Floss?
- 是 草莓味的那种 - 噢 没问题
- Yeah, the strawberry kind. - Oh, sure.
晚安 小熊
Good night, Bear.
克雷塞熊熊
Creasy Bear.
在祈祷什么?
What's that one for?
祈祷瓜德罗普圣女像
La Virgin de Guadalupe.
为生意 为丰田 为福特
Business. For T oyota, for Ford.
如果一个人死了 也许她会救活另一个
If one dies, maybe she can resurrect the other one.
我不知道
I don't know.
她喜欢他
She likes him.
- 你在说什么? - 克雷塞
- What are you talking about? - Creasy.
苹塔喜欢他
Pita likes him.
苹塔喜欢学校
Pita loves school.
如果有吸血鬼伯爵把她带走 苹塔也会喜欢 亲爱的
Pita wouldlove Count Dracula ifhe took herback there, honey.
好吧
Okay?
- 嘿 你没事吧? - 不知道
- Hey. Are you okay? - I don't know.
没事吧?
Okay?
我不知道 莉莎
I don't know, Lisa.
尽量吧
I 'm trying.
来吧 小鸟
Come on, Bird.
对了 对了 来吧
That's right. That's right. Come on.
好了 去找艾美里欧吧
All right. Home to Emilio.
你自由了 宝贝
You're home free, baby.
- 从哪来的 克雷塞? - 美国
- Where are you from, Creasy? - The U.S.
- 我知道 哪个州? - 没特定的州
- I know, but which state? - No state in particular.
你可以边开车边谈话
You can drive and talk at the same time.
不行 苹塔 拜托了 让我专心工作
No, I can't, Pita, so, please, let me just do myjob.
你会留下吗?
Are you going to stay?
我的上一任保镖走了
My last bodyguard left.
有人出了比我们高的价
Somebody gave him more money than we could.
那么我就是便宜货?
I guess that makes me a bargain then, huh?
作为黑人 在墨西哥 当保镖是好事还是坏事?
Being black is that a positive or negative for a bodyguard in Mexico?
时间会证明的
Time will tell.
过去6天墨西哥城发生了 24宗绑架案
There were 24 kidnappings in Mexico City in the last six days.
- 每天4宗 - 是吗?
- Four a day. - Yeah?
- 24宗? - 24宗 你怎么想 克雷塞?
- Twenty- four? - Twenty- four. What do you think about that, Creasy?
- 我认为你知道得太多了 - 谢谢
- I think thatyou know entirely more than you should. - Well, thankyou.
你好 米格
Hola, Miguel.
- 再见 - 你得签字
- See you later. - You have to sign.
- 什么? - 你得签名 出示你的身份
- What? - You have to sign in, show them your I.D.
早安 来吧
Buenos dias. Come on.
就那里
Right there.
- 你好 曼雷 - 你好 苹塔
- Hola, Manuel. - Hola, Pita.
- 你好 苹塔 - 你好
- Hola, Pita!- Hola!
苹塔! 见到你回来真高兴
Pita! It's so good to have you back.
安娜修女 这是我的新任保镖 克雷塞
Sister Anna, this is my new bodyguard, Creasy.
安娜修女 女校长
Sister Anna, the headmistress.
克雷塞先生
Senor Creasy.
快点 要上课了
Hurry. Class is about to begin.
- 快去 - 再见 克雷塞
- Go, go. - Bye, Creasy.
- 太太 - 你得好好照料苹塔
- Madre. - You must look after our Pita.
她今天迟到可不好
It is not good that she's late today.
很抱歉 我 我得适应一下规章 不会再发生了 我保证
I'm very sorry. I, uh I'll have to get used to the rules. It won't happen again.
请勿见怪 但我对你的职业水平感到遗憾
No offense, but I regret thatyour profession needs to exist.
我也是 太太 我也是
So do I, Madre. So do I.
你明白 上帝之手 该怎么做吗?
Do you ever see the hand of God in what you do?
不 做这行没多久
No, not for a long time.
圣经说 不可为恶所胜
The Bible says, "Be not overcome of evil, but overcome"
- 而要以善胜恶 - 而要以善胜恶
"Overcome evil with good."
罗马书 12章21节上有
我是只迷途的羔羊 太太
I'm the sheep that got lost, Madre.
你小时候喜欢上学吗 克雷塞?
When you were a kid, Creasy, did you like school?
- 我不记得了 - 你不记得了?
- I don't remember. - You don't remember?
不 我不记得 不 我不喜欢
No, I don't remember. It, uh Nah, I didn't like it.
为什么?
Why not?
因为不是像你那种学校 苹塔
Because it wasn't a school likeyours.
也没有 没有安娜修女
There was no, uh no Sister Anna.
不开心吗?
Wereyou unhappy?
苹塔 不开心是你心理在作怪 我真的不记得了
Being unhappy, Pita, that's a state of mind. I really don't remember.
你的手怎么了?
What happened to your hand?
- 天生缺陷 - 不 不是
- It's a birth defect. - No, it's not.
听着 别再问了 好吗?
Look, no more questions, okay?
- 这不算什么问题 - 听上去就是问题
- It really wasn't a question. - It sounded like a question.
听着 我是来工作的 嘿!
Look, I got a job to do. Hey!
不 谢谢 谢谢 不要
No. Gracias. Gracias. No. No.
听着 我是收了钱才保护你的
Listen to me. I'm being paid to protect you, okay?
不要! 不要! 我收钱做你保镖
No, no, no. I'm being paid to be your bodyguard.
看着我 我收钱不是做朋友
Look at me. I'm not beingpaid to beyourfriend.
我收钱是做保镖 所以别再问了 就这样 结束
I'm beingpaid to protectyou, so no more questions. That's it. Period.
- 听见吗? - 是
- You hear me? - Yes.
- 别哭 - 我没哭
- And no crying. - I 'm not crying.
别哭出来
Well, don't start.
你会懂的 这是工作
You gotta understand, this is a job.
为了让我工作
In order for me to do
为了让 等等
In order for Wait a minute.
请进
Yeah, come in.
克雷塞先生
Mr. Creasy.
我只是想知道 你该有的都有了
I just wanted to make sure you have everything you need.
是 很好 谢谢
I'm fine, thanks.
吃的还习惯吗? 因为玛丽亚告诉我你没吃
Is the food all right? 'Cause, uh, Maria told meyou didn't eat.
是 伙食很好
Uh yeah, the food is great.
只是我今晚不饿
I just wasn't that hungry tonight.
你在看圣经?
Soyou, uh, read the Bible?
是 有时看
Yeah, sometimes.
- 有用吗? - 是 有时有用
- Does it help? - Yeah, sometimes.
- 能和你谈一会吗? - 当然
- Can I talk to you for a minute? - Sure.
跟苹塔相处得怎样?
How are you doing with Pita?
很好
Fine. Fine.
一旦她明白我不是她的新玩具 她就会好的
Soon as she figures out that I'm not her new toy, we'll be fine.
- 她告诉我了 - 很好
- Yeah, she told me about that. - Okay.
- 你没孩子 是吗? - 告诉过你 没有
- You don't have children, do you? - I told you I didn't.
他们要东西的时候会变得很固执
Well, they can be tenacious when theywant something.
- 而苹塔只是想交朋友 - 好吧
- And Pita just wants to be friends. - Okay.
但你付钱是让我保护她 不是做朋友
Butyou're paying me to protect her, right? Not to be her friend.
对吧?
Right?
那么
So, uh
听着 也许我不太适合
Iook, maybe this isn't gonna work out.
也许你先生应该找个 更擅于社交的人
Maybe your husband should find somebodywho's a little more sociable.
你说得没错
No, you're right.
你收了钱是保护她
You're being paid to protect her
我有信心你能做好
and I'm confident thatyou'll do that.
我明天和你们一起上学 希望大家相安无事
I'll be coming with you tomorrow. I hope that's all right.
你认为上帝会宽恕我们做的吗?
You think God will forgive us for what we've done?
我厌倦杀人 雷
I'm tired ofkillin ', Ray.
上帝会宽恕我们做的吗?
You think God will forgive us for what we 've done?
凭我这状态 我连 我连死人都保护不了
In my state, I couldn 't I couldn 't guard a corpse.
不停地说话
Talk all the time.
你知道这个我不在行
You know, I'm no good at that.
你知道他们怎么说
You know how they say
子弹会说真话?
a bullet always tells the truth?
喂
Yeah.
- 嘿 - 克雷塞
- Hey. - Crease.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
嘿 听着 你有过
Hey, listen, you- you ever have a
一把打不出子弹的9mm手枪吗?
a nine- millimeter round that didn't go off?
是啊 开不了火
Well, yeah. Failure to fire.
我知道 开不了火 然后
I know. Failure to fire and- and- and, uh
扣动扳机 然后
You know, I pulled the trigger and and and
什么也没发生
click, nothing.
你在说枪管哑火
You're talking about a bad primer.
是 是 是
Yeah, I Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
但我 对 太近 枪管顶得太近
But I You know, right, dimple. Dimple on the primer.
也许
That may be.
就像我们过去说的
Well, like we used to say
子弹会说真话
a bullet always tells the truth.
克雷塞?
Crease?
- 你没事吧? - 是
- You all right? - Yeah.
你对着什么开枪?
What wereyou shooting at?
是 对不起 对不起吵醒你
Yeah, I'm sorry, Ray. I'm sorry I wokeyou.
不 没事 我 我在看电视
No, i- it's okay. Nothin'. I was watchin' TV.
好吧
Okay.
All right.
苹塔 有铅笔吗?
Pita, you have a pencil?
谢谢
Thankyou.
适应这里的交通不容易
It's hard to get used to the traffic down here.
是 对不起
Yeah. I'm very sorry.
- 再见 宝贝 - 再见
- See you, baby. - All right. See you later.
- 嘿 别忘了毛巾 - 噢 谢谢
- Hey. Don't forget your towel. - Oh, thankyou.
再见 早安
Bye. Buenas dias.
- 你是游泳健将 - 从来没赢过
- You're a strong swimmer. - I neverwin.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 我该怎么做? - 你认为你该怎么做?
- So what do I do? - What do you think you should do?
你在水里游得最快 在街上却走得最慢
You're the fastest one in the water, the slowest one off the blocks.
- 你认为是什么意思? 该怎么做? - 赶快走出街区
- What do you think that means? What do you gotta do? - Get faster off the blocks.
没错 赶快走出街区
Get faster offthe blocks.
- 三星期后有个游泳大赛 - 是吗?
- Our big swim meet is in three weeks. - Yeah?
- 我要参加150米自由泳比赛 - 你行的
- I was gonna enter the 1 50 freestyle. - Yeah,you'll be fine.
能行的
You'll be okay.
- 我还是会很慢 - 你不慢
- I'll still be slow. - You're not slow.
我从来没游进过前三名
I never finish better than third.
也许你是慢了点
All right. Maybe you are slow then.
今晚我们请到了改革报社的 玛丽安娜 葛蕾诺
来谈谈关于绑架事件
你认为墨西哥 的绑架事件该由谁来负责?
这是有组织的犯罪活动 并非随意绑架事件
它们不是哥伦比亚那种政治绑架
快走 小鸟
Vamos, Bird!
走呀
Vamos!
它怎么会在外面?
How do you think he got out?
- 我放了它的 - 最好让其自由 是吗?
- I let him go. - It's better to be free, right?
对它是没错
It's better for him.
其实是它令我心烦
Actually, he was driving me crazy.
晚安
Good night.
- 几天后再见 好吗? 我爱你 - 好的 我爱你
- See you in a couple of days. I love you. - All right. Love you.
乖点 快点 莉莎
Be good. Come on, Lise.
- 我们会在底特律打电话给你 - 好的
- All right, sweetheart. We'll call you from Detroit. - Okay.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
- I love you. - Love you.
- 好了 再见 宝贝 - 太太
- Okay. Bye, honey. - Senora.
- 再见 - 噢 谢谢
- Bye. - Oh. Gracias.
- 再见 宝贝 - 再见
- Okay. Bye, honey! - Bye.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
- I love you. - Love you.
真不想离开她
I hate leaving her.
集中精力?
Concentratin'?
闭上眼睛?
Eyes are closed?
怎么了?
What happened?
- 吓我一跳 - 吓一跳? 枪声吓不了我
- I flinched. - You flinched? The gunshot holds no fear.
- 说一遍 - 枪声吓不了我
- Say it. - The gunshot holds no fear.
枪声吓不了我! 说一遍
The gunshot holds no fear! Say it.
- 枪声吓不了我 - 大声点!
- The gunshot holds no fear. - Louder!
- 枪声吓不了我! - 大声点!
- The gunshot holds no fear! - Louder!
- 枪声吓不了我! - 很好
- The gunshot holds no fear! - That's good.
你释放了你的声音
You welcome the sound.
其实是声音释放了你
In fact, it's the sound that sets you free.
在声音释放你之前 你就是这石块上的囚犯
You are a prisoner on this block until that sound sets you free.
- 准备好了? - 是
- Areyou ready? Areyou ready? - Yes. Yes.
- 一切就绪? - 嗯
- Areyou set? - Uh- huh.
- 克雷塞? - 嗯?
- Creasy? - Hmm?
- 什么叫妃子? - 为什么问这个?
- What's a concubine? - Why do you ask?
历史书上写着的
It's in my history book.
- 噢 - 就像是妻子 对吗?
- Oh. - It's like a wife, right?
是啊 是 这是 让我看看?
Yeah. Yes, uh Can I see that?
- 就像是妻子 - 就这里
- Kind of a wife. - Right there.
但中国皇帝却有1000个妃子
But the emperor ofChina had 1,000 ofthem.
呃
Um
好吧 如今在西方 实行的是一夫一妻制
Okay, like nowadays in- in the West, they have one husband for one wife.
但是在古代文化中 他们有
But in the olden time cultures, they had, uh
你知道 不同的 不同的规矩
you know, different uh, different rules.
- 怎么了? 对丈夫感到可悲? - 是啊
- Why, you feel sorry for the husband? - Yeah.
你能想象我有1000个妈妈吗?
Can you imagine my mom multiplied by a thousand?
克雷塞 你笑了
Creasy. You're smiling.
- 什么? - 你笑了
- What? - You were smiling.
- 没 没笑 刚才也没笑 - 你笑了
- No, I'm not. No, I was not. - You were.
- 现在没笑 刚才笑了 - 不 你笑了 我没笑
- You're not now, but you were. - You were smiling. I wasn't.
- 你笑了 - 什么时候?
- You were. - When?
- 就在5秒前 - 我没笑
- Like five seconds ago. - I'm not smiling.
- 1秒前还笑了 - 不 你说5秒 现在6秒了
A second ago you were. - You said five seconds ago. Now that's six.
- 6秒前我没笑. - 好吧 10秒前
Six seconds ago I wasn't smiling. - Ten seconds ago.
10秒前我笑了 好吧 接下来的10秒看谁先笑
Ten seconds ago I was smiling. Okay, in the next 10 seconds, let's see who smiles first.
- 你已经笑了 瞧 你笑了 - 唔!
- You smiled already. See? You did. - Mmm!
- 不 我没笑 是假笑 - 是 你
- No, that wasn't a That was a smirk. - Yeah, you
那不是微笑 假笑是不同的
That's not a smile. A smirk is different.
都是S开头的 但他们不一样 做你的功课
They both start with "S," but they're not the same Do your homework.
你笑了
You were.
砰!
Bang!
停 停 停 回来 回来
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop. Come back, come back.
砰!
Bang!
停 停 停 过来
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop. Come here.
快点 快点 各就各位
Hurry up, hurry up. Set.
砰!
Bang!
听到枪声别害怕 明白吗?
You don't flinch when you hear the gunshot, understand?
听枪声 别抢先
You listen for the sound. You don't anticipate.
专心听枪声 明白吗?
Concentrate on the sound. You understand me?
他们要超过你了! 快 快 快 停 停
They're gaining on you! Go, go, go, go, go, go! Stop! Stop!
快点 上来 再来 再来
Come on, get out. Let's go again. Let's go again.
- 谢谢 过来 宝贝女儿 - 爸爸!
- Gracias. Come here, girl! - Daddy!
想死你了
Oh, I missed you so much.
- 我也想你 - 还好吗? 我有个惊喜给你
- I missed you too. - How are you doing? I got a surprise for you.
- 是什么? - 准备好了?
- You do? - Ready?
- 嗯 - 你帮我买了只小狗!
- Huh? - You got me a dog! You finally got me a dog!
总算帮我买了只小狗! 天啊!
- 喜欢吗? - 噢 天哪
- What do you think? - Oh, my gosh.
- 我要的就是它! 叫什么名字? - 山姆 和爸爸一样
- Just what I wanted. What's his name? - Sam, like Dad.
好极了! 快来 山姆!
Great! Come on, Sam! Come on, Sam!
- 状态 - 嗯
- State. - Mm- hmm.
喜马拉雅的不丹王国
Bhutan. It's a Himalayan kingdom.
不久前他们的皇室出了事
Theywere havingsomeproblems with theirroyal familynot that long ago.
好了
- Mm- hmm. - Okay.
还有问题吗?
Any more questions?
- 有女友吗 克雷塞? - 什么?
- Do you have a girlfriend? - What?
- 有女友吗? - 没有
- Do you have a girlfriend? - No.
不管什么问题 都应该与历史有关 好吗?
What kind ofquestion is that? You're supposed to be studying history.
- 那是历史 克雷塞的历史 - 不 问古代历史
- That is history. Creasy history. - No, that's ancient history.
- 别再问了 不管 - 谁是你的初恋女友?
- No more questions. - Who was your very first girlfriend?
没有 她就是不关你的事
Nonya. Nonya business. That's who.
- 好吗? - 嗨
- Okay? - Hi.
明天你送完苹塔后 可以送我去弄头发吗?
Tomorrow afteryou drop off Pita, could you take me to get my hair done?
- 是 太太 - 那好
- Yes, ma'am. - All right.
继续学你们的历史吧
Well, um, I'll leave you two to your history.
- 晚安 - 晚安 宝贝
- Good night. - Goodnight, honey.
- 可以问我了吗? - 问你什么?
- Okay, now ask me. - Ask you what?
砰!
bang!
快 苹塔 快 快
Go, Pita, go. Go! Go, go, go, go!
快 快 快
Go, go, go, go, go.
- 棒极了! 太好了! - 棒极了! 太好了!
- Bravo! Muy bien!
- 10.99秒 - 耶!
- 10.99. - Yes!
喔!
Whoo!
- 游得很辛苦 克雷塞 - 是吗? 没有什么辛不辛苦
- I'm tough, Creasy. - No such thing as tough.
只有训练或不训练
There's trained, then there's untrained.
- 你选哪样? - 训练
- Now, which are you? - Trained.
训练 好 继续再来
Trained. Okay. Let's go again.
- 拿着 - 站在终点那里
- Here. - Stand here near the finish line.
好的 嘿
Okay. Hey.
枪声释放我之前 我是石块上的囚犯
I'm a prisoner in the block until the gunshot sets me free.
- 没错 想赢就别笑 别胡闹 - 好的
- Don't smile, don't fool around if you want to win. - Okay.
- 想赢吗? 训不训练? - 训练
- You want to win? Trained or untrained? - Trained.
去吧
Go.
- 克雷塞先生 真是幸会 - 噢 幸会 太太
- SenorCreasy, nice to See you. - Oh, good to see you, Madre.
苹塔的双亲去华瑞兹出差 我
Pita's parents are away on business in Juarez. I was
今天你就是她父亲
Todayyou are her father.
第一名是 苹塔 拉莫斯!
Pita Ramos!
我赢了! 克雷塞! 我赢了!
I won! Creasy! I won!
- 好的 - 我赢了!
- Okay. - I won!
- 以前我们年轻的时候 - 我年轻的时候
- Once upon a time, when we were young - When I was young.
我们年轻 他更年轻的时候
Well, when we were young and he was younger
所有人都不愿帮我们
all heads turned ourway.
我们说好 有福同享 有难同当
We made a deal to take the world together.
是啊 有天我接到一个电话 他说
Yeah, then one day I got a call, and he said
我恋爱了! 我恋爱了!
I'm in love! I'm in love!
我要搬去墨西哥
And I'm moving to Mexico. "
然后 我说
AndI said
那说好的计划呢 怎么办?
What happened to the plan? What happened to it?
我说 计划就这么地了
I said, "The plan's right here."
是啊 那我该怎么办?
Yeah. Yeah. And what'd I do?
我挂了电话 后来遇见了阿莉西亚
I hung up, then I met Alicia
然后我走了 噢 现在我明白你了! 明白了
and then I went, "Oh, now I gotyou! I gotyou."
我懂了 可以吻她吗?
I got it. Can I kiss her? Is that
绝对可以! 嘿! 你们干嘛?
Absolutely! Hey, what are you doing?
- 被他抓住了 - 好了 我想现在是时候了
- You got me. - Okay, I think now is a good a time as any.
我自己的钱买的
I bought it with my own money.
打开它
Open it.
是圣犹大像 免死护身符
It's St.Jude, patron saint oflost causes.
哇
Wow.
应得的
Well deserved.
谢谢 苹塔 很美
Thankyou, Pita. It's beautiful.
不用谢
You're welcome.
- 爸爸 - 是 宝贝?
- Dad. - Yes, sweetie?
能谈几句吗?
Can I talk to you?
可以
Yes.
我不想弹琴 我想游泳
I don't want to play piano. I want to swim.
不讨论这个 好吗?
It's not open for discussion, honey, okay?
罗兹先生是很有名的钢琴老师 如果他肯收你为徒
Mr. Lozzi's a very, very famous teacher, and ifhe accepts you as his student
你就得弹琴
you're gonna play the piano.
算了
Whatever.
宝贝
Baby.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
- I love you. - I love you.
- 我只想给你最好的 懂吗? - 懂
- I just want what's best for you, you know that? - Okay.
好吧 宝贝
Okay, honey.
如果你把我手指都弄断 克雷塞 再把它们绑在一起
if you broke all my fingers, then taped them back together
我就不能弹琴 但还能游泳
I wouldn't be able to play piano, but I could still swim.
山姆 坐回去
Sam, get back.
别做个爱哭鬼 坚强点
Don't be a crybaby. You're tougher than that.
坐好 坐好 坐好
Sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit.
- 记得借铅笔的那天吗? - 记得
- Remember the dayyou wanted the pencil? - Yeah.
我知道为什么
I know why.
- 是嘛? - 你想记下那车的车牌
- Yeah? - You wanted the license number off ofthat car.
我也写在了我的笔记本上
I wrote it down in my notebook.
除了最后一位数都记下了
I got it all but the last number.
好的 我会帮你搞齐最后一位 会打嗝吗?
I'll get it from you lat Can you belch?
就像打饱嗝那种打嗝 会打饱嗝吗?
Burp. Can you burp?
很好 非常好
That's good. That's very good.
- 我刚喝了可乐 - 好了 听着
- I just had a Coke. - All right. Listen.
这个老师非常有名
Now, this teacher, this famous teacher
他教很多有钱人家的孩子教交响乐曲 是吧?
He teaches a lot of rich kids and plays for the symphonies, right?
- 对 - 在你练琴时 隔几分钟打1次嗝
- Right. - You belch every few minutes while you're practicing.
- 好的 - 你道歉 但还是不断打嗝
- Okay. - You apologize to him, butyou keep belching.
- 那样会触犯他的神经 是吧? - 好的
- You'll offend every sensibility he has. - Okay.
很好 24小时后你就能 回到游泳池 我保证
Very good. You'll be back in the pool in 24 hours, I guarantee you.
对吧 山姆?
Right, Sam?
- 喂 - 露苹塔 拉莫斯
- Hola. - Lupita Ramos?
送给你 克雷塞
Foryou, Creasy.
谢谢
Thankyou.
- 这样好吗? - 好
- How does this look? - Good.
- 好 - 唔?
- Good. - Hmm?
- 你好 苹塔 - 你好
- Hola, Pita. - Hola.
- 再见 - 再见 要多久?
- Bye. - Bye.
- 1小时 - 谢谢
Gracias.
苹塔
Pita.
苹塔!
Pita!
快跑!
Run!
克雷塞!
Creasy!
克雷塞 克雷塞
Creasy. Creasy.
克雷塞!
Creasy!
我做不到
I can't
快点!
Come on!
约翰 克雷塞因涉嫌谋害
John W. Creasyis underarrest forthe murder oftwo police officers
两名法警而遭拘捕
oftheJudicial Police.
克雷塞!
Creasy!
并涉嫌卷入绑架案
Also involved in the kidnapping of
这就是约翰 克雷塞
这位叫约翰 克雷塞
的美国公民
因枪杀两名法警
而遭拘捕
并涉嫌卷入
露苹塔 马丁 拉莫斯的绑架案
拉米勒斯警长
有记录显示两名被害警官
在出事当时并未执勤公务
请问他们为何身着制服
驾驶巡逻警车?
我只知道他们英勇牺牲了
那是当然
但他们在绑架现场究竟干嘛?
他们是否因异常好运而出名?
他们因贪污而臭名昭著
现在又因其死讯而大快人心
让一让
Excuse me.
放松 好吗? 放松 山米
Everybody relax, okay? Relax, Sammy.
我知道她是你宝贝女儿
I know she's your little girl.
但我说一切会没事 就会没事
When I tell you everything's gonna be all right, everything's gonna be all right.
拉莫斯先生
SenorRamos.
很遗憾 真的很遗憾
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
威特 范托斯 法警部反绑组的
Victor Fuentes, Anti- Kidnapping Division, PoliciaJudicial.
打扰一下 我是乔丹 卡夫斯 他的家庭律师
Excuse me. I'm Jordan Kalfus. I'm the family attorney.
请说得慢点 我的俄语比英语要好
Speak slower, please. My Russian is better than my English.
我正在进行谈判 我们无需也不必警方的协助
Well, I'm conducting the negotiations, and we neither need norwant police assistance.
我们会 我们会自己解决
We're gonna We're gonna handle this thing ourselves.
拉莫斯先生 你女儿遭绑架时
SenorRamos, two police officers were killed
有两名警官被杀
duringyour daughter's abduction.
这是来自宣传部的授权证明书
I have a written order from Ministerio Publico
我们的介入授权属非正式性质
authorizing our participation ex- officio.
如果你想跟首席检察官里亚斯通话 请便
if you want to speak to Attorney General Diaz, it's on me.
不必? 那好吧
No. Okay.
绑匪会叫你去单独交钱
The kidnapperwill tell you to deliver the money alone.
绝不要去
Porfavor, don't do that
否则你会发现自己进入了真正的墨西哥地狱
oryou will find yourself in a real Mexican hell.
没马拉其乐队 没龙舌酒 也没有苹塔
No mariachi. No tequila and no Pita.
克雷塞
Crease.
当我听说是这家医院 我太高兴了
When I heardit was this hospital, I was so pleased.
这附近有家糕饼店
There is a pastry shop nearby.
帝家道糕饼店 他们的糕饼是全墨西哥最好的
Delgado's. They have the best pastries in Mexico.
米格・洛桑诺
Oh, Miguel Manzano
联邦调查局局长
director of the A.F.I .
并是国际警察署 罗马分局的前任局长
and a former director oflnterpol in Rome.
- 你是...? - 他的朋友 雷本
- And you are? - Friend ofhis. Rayburn.
雷本?
Rayburn?
喂
Hola.
你爱你的女儿吗 拉莫斯先生?
Do you love your daughter, Senor Ramos?
是的 爱
Yes. Yes.
- 想再见到她吗? - 是的 想
- Do you want to see her again? - Yes, I do.
先生 如果你女儿的命
Senor, if your daughter's life
对你就像对我那样重要
is as important to you as it is to me
就照我说的做
you will do as I say.
- 行吗? - 好的 行
- Yes? - Okay. Yes.
- 克雷塞 听得见吗? - 呃
- Crease. Can you hear me? - Hmm.
你干掉了他们四个
You got four of them. All dead.
苹塔
- Pita. - It's, uh
已经两天了 他们在商谈赎金
It's been two days. They're negotiating a ransom.
这些事要花时间 克雷塞先生
These things take time, Mr. Creasy.
克雷塞
Crease.
别这样 好吗?
Don't fuck with me, all right?
你有1000万吗? 有这笔钱吗?
Do you have the 10 million? Do you have the money?
- 是 我们有 - 现在 如果照我说的做
- Yes, we have the money. - Now if you do as I say
你女儿会被毫发无伤地还给你
the girl will be returned exactly as she was taken.
但若你在过程中耍一点点手段
But if you deviate from the process in any way
以瓜德罗普圣女的名义
我发誓 你再也见不到她
I swear, you will never see her again.
我明白 听着 我也信瓜德
I understand. Listen, I- I too worship la Virgin de Guadalupe.
我问你明不明白?
I ask you if you understand.
你好 先生 我是拉莫斯先生的律师
Hello, sir. This is, uh, Mr. Ramos's attorney.
现在他时逢艰难期 但他明白
He's going through a very difficult time here, but he understands.
那你明白? 重复交钱指示
Do you understand? Repeat the drop instructions.
好的 1000万美金会分装在
Okay, the money, 10 million, U.S., will be divided into
2个15加仑的黑色帆布袋中 每袋500万
two 1 5- gallon black canvas bags, each containing five million
钱在银行由K.R.代理加盖证实章
which will be checked at the bank by the K. R. agent
然后用武装车运回家 在那里我们再转运上交钱车
then driven to the house in an armored car where it will be transferred to the delivery car.
车胎扁了
You got a flat tire here.
打给你的
This is for you.
喂? 是
Hel lo. Yeah.
听着 我要其它人开山默尔去
Listen, I need a driver to drive Samuel.
不 为什么?
No. Why?
他心脏不好 有心脏病
He's got a bad ticker. He's got a heart condition.
听着 他受不了紧张加重压
Look, he's a nervous kid who doesn't respond well to stress.
好吧 但不要用大马力车
All right. But the carwill not be powerful.
拆掉尾箱盖子 用仆人的 法利安 阿卡布科 车
Remove the trunk lid. Use the maid's Valiant Acapulco.
你们于凌晨一时到达拉黛安娜喷泉广场
You willarrive at La Diana Fountain at 1:00 a.m.
你沿着中央岛开两圈
You will drive around the circle two times.
山默尔需脱下衬衣 并将其伸出窗外
Samuel will remove his shirt and hold it out the window
以鉴别该车
to I. D. the car.
东南角有个电话亭
There is a payphone on the southeast corner.
电话会响 你去接然后等候指示
The phone will ring. He will answer and wait for instructions.
电话上面有地图 照着去做
There is a map on the top ofthe phone. Follow it.
很好
Perfecto.
- 你在干嘛! 他说过不准打电话! - 放松 放松
- What are you doi ng? He said no phones! - Relax. Relax.
- 我只是想保护你女儿 - 快带我去
- I 'm just trying to protect your daughter.- J ust get me there, please.
- 怎么回事? - 医院会变成很危险的地方
- What's going on? - Hospitals can be very dangerous places.
尤其是杀了两名贪污警官之后
Especiallywhen you have killed two corrupt cops.
把钱放进白色车的尾箱内
Leave the money in the trunk ofthe white car.
然后回你的车
Then return to your car.
别回头
Do not look back.
出什么事了 伙计?
有埋伏!
记住 我是职业选手
Remember, I'm a professional.
你若守信 我不食言
if you keep your word, I will keep mine.
- 喂? - 拉莫斯先生
- Hel lo. - Mr. Ramos.
你出卖了我 你害死了我侄子
You betrayed me. You killed my nephew.
你拿了我的钱
You took my money.
拉莫斯先生
Senor Ramos
上帝与你孩子同在
好吧 你们都给我滚出去! 从我家里滚出去!
All right. Get out of here, all ofyou. Get the fuck out of my house!
好了 我是莉莎・拉莫斯
Okay, this is Lisa.
苹塔的妈妈
I'm Pita's mother.
你侄子的事我感到万分遗憾 但我恳求你
And I'm very sorry forwhatever happened to your nephew, but I beg you
请别伤害我女儿
这次对话未被录音
This conversation is not being recorded.
你现在正直接与我谈判
抱歉 真是抱歉 但愿我们能再谈 太太
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry. I wish we had talked sooner, senora.
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
现在已经太晚了
Now it is too late.
滚出去! 滚出我的家! 滚!
Fuck off!. Get the fuck out of my fucking house now!
滚出去! 滚出去!
Get out! Get out!
嘿
Hey.
嘿 雷 是你吗?
Hey, Ray.
- 我在哪里? - 好像是家兽医院
- Where am I? - Well, it looks like a dog hospital.
洛桑诺怕有警察会杀你
Manzano was afraid the cops were gonna kill you.
还好吗?
How ya doin', Doc?
什么事?
What's the matter?
她死了 死了 克雷塞
She's de dead, Crease.
事情乱了套
It's a mess.
有人劫了赎金
Somebody hijacked the drop, and, uh
绑匪的侄子被杀了
the kidnapper's nephew was killed
所以 他们杀害了苹塔
so he k he killed Pita.
他胸部及腹部中弹
我们已帮他的肺穿孔补了气
他有幸还活着 若不休养会死
他还需住院多久?
约一个月
不
No.
你是否能认出其中的任何一人?
Did you recognize any of these men?
不 也许我也是疑犯?
No. Does that make me a suspect?
不
No.
为了方便起见 但不是
It would be convenient, but no.
也许你该给我看些墨西哥 警察的照片
Um, maybeyou should show me some pictures of some Mexican cops.
- 我们或许能有点线索 - 这些都是警察
- Maybe we'll get somewhere then. - Those were all policemen.
法警中的败类
Bad judicial cops.
受庇护于一个兄弟会
Protected by a brotherhood.
兄弟会?
Brotherhood?
一个兄弟会 叫做 拉曼达
A brotherhood called La Hermandad.
行了吗?
You all set?
- 嗯? - 右手放这里
- Hmm? - Right arm. Here.
- 没事吧? - 是 我没事
- Okay? - Yeah. I'm all right.
走吧
Let's go.
- 有人跟踪我们 - 是 露易丝・兰
- Somebody's on us. - Yeah. Lois Lane.
- 谁? - 玛丽安娜什么的 为改革报工作
- Who? - Mariana something, works for Reforma.
报社记者
Newspaperjournalist.
也许她认为你是抢手的新闻
Maybe she thinks you're a scoop.
我会把你送到边界
I 'll get you up to the border.
我朋友会带你去圣地亚哥 送你到海军医院
A friend of mine will take you to San Diego, drop you right at the naval hospital.
- 我不去 雷 - 你想怎样?
- I'm not going, Ray. - What are you gonna do?
就去犯罪现场 她会跟来
Let's take a ride by the crime scene. She can follow us.
早安
Buenos dias.
克雷塞先生?
Mr. Creasy?
很多人都在找你
A lot of people are looking for you.
我是 玛丽安娜 格茜亚 葛蕾诺
I'm Mariana Garcia Guerrero.
改革报社的记者
Reporter for Reforma.
- 幸会 - 我在街对面发现了这个
- Nice to meet you. - I found this across the street.
打开它
Open it.
这是 圣死 死亡礼拜
It's Santa Muerte. Death worship.
- 他们对你下了诅咒 - 呃 晚了点
- They've put a curse onyou. - Ha. They're a little late.
- 打算怎么做? - 我想开车离开
- What are you going to do? - I'm gonna get in my truck and leave.
我能帮你
I can help you.
有个兄弟会叫 拉曼达
There's a brotherhood called La Hermandad.
专门庇护政府高官及贪污警察
It protects high- ranking government officials, corrupt police
并策划犯罪 我难以渗入其中
and organized crime at a level that is too difficult for me to reach.
知道了
Okay.
我认为你和 苹塔 拉莫斯 都是这个组织的受害者
And I think thatyou and Lupita Ramos are victims ofthis organization.
我要揭发内幕 我想跟你谈 说出你的事 那样我才能帮你
I want to expose them. Talk to me, give meyour story, then I can helpyou.
拜托了
Please.
帮我做什么?
Help me do what?
你能帮我做什么?
You're gonna help me do what?
你是外地人 不是吗?
You're a stranger here, no?
没错
That's right.
出外得靠朋友
You're going to need friends that know theirway around.
好的
Okay.
好吧 朋友会帮我
Okay, friend that's gonna help me.
幸会了 叫你司机下次开车别跟得太近
A pleasure to meetyou. Tell your driver to keep his distance next time.
好吗 朋友?
All right, friend?
好
Si.
你晚饭时分就能到美国本土
You'll be stateside by supper time.
我最需要帮手 雷
I'm gonna need some help first though, Ray.
你再流血 可能性命不保
if you don'tstop bleeding, you won't last a daythe shapeyou're in.
- 那算帮还是不帮? - 帮
- Is that a yes or is that a no? - Yeah.
但是我杀过人 告诉过你
But I'm done killing. I told you that.
- 行了 - 还有什么要帮忙的?
- Okay. - Anything else is yours.
- 这是去打仗 克雷塞 - 我就是这意思
- You're talking about war. - Exactlywhat I'm talking about.
能帮我吗?
Can you help me?
- 是 - 好
- Yeah. - Good.
克雷塞
Creasy.
你能爱我 克雷塞 你是我最好的熊熊
我爱你克雷塞熊熊!
- 你在这里干嘛? - 哦
- What are you doing here? - Oh.
来拿我的东西
Came to get my stuff.
找不到圣经 我想是放这里了
Couldn't find my Bible. I thought it might be in here.
- 我借去了 - 好的
- I borrowed it. - Okay.
真不可思议 嗯?
It's crazy, huh?
一星期老想着去俱乐部的人
One weekwe're figuring out which nightclub to go to
接着也会看圣经
and the next thing I'm reading the Bible.
是好事 留着它吧
It's a good thing. You hold on to it.
我不断在想 如果我们没有
I keep thinking, if onlywe hadn't
发生那事
It's like, um
我的一生 我一直都在想的
mywhole life, all I've everthought about
是我自己能得到些什么
was what I could get for myself.
甚至和我宝贝一起的时候
Even with my own baby.
她是那么的需要我 有时
She needed me so much, and sometimes
我感到我没什么能给她
I felt like I had nothing to give her.
只是 我不知该怎么做
Just, um, I don't know what to do.
- 你打算怎么做? - 尽我所能
- What are you gonna do? - What I do best.
我要宰了他们
I'm gonna kill 'em.
所有涉及的人 所有得利的人
Anyone who was involved. Anybodywho profited from it.
所有瞪眼看我的人
Anybodywho opens their eyes at me.
把他们赶尽杀绝
You kill 'em all.
布朗宁枪
Yla Browning.
改革 报社
喂?
Hola.
喂 是我
Yeah, it's me.
- 克雷塞先生 - 我需要牌照
- Mr. Creasy. - Okay. I need the license
不 对不起
Well, no, excuse me.
我需要名字和地址 人的牌照号是C5TK8
I need the name and address of someone whose license number is C- 5- T- K- 8.
是C- 5- T- K- 8
That's C- 5- T- K- 8.
除最后一位数我都有了 要10种可能的匹配
I got everything but the last digit, so I need 10 possible matches.
几时才能查出这10个匹配者?
And when do I find out which ofthe 10 it is?
- 尽力吧 - 去哪里找你?
- Eventually. - Well, where do I reach you?
我打给你
I'll call you.
联邦调查局 墨西哥城
知道他是谁吗?
知道他过去16年都做了什么吗?
专门做 镇压暴乱
泰国 巴基斯坦
约旦 安哥拉 黎巴嫩 是 我都知道
Jordan, Angola, Lebanon. Yes, I know all ofthat.
他是个杀手 你居然想帮他查证车主资料?
He's an assassin. And you want to help him identify the owner ofa car for him?
他能去我们去不了的地方
如果你不愿用他 我愿意
- 玛丽安娜 - 是
- Mariana. - Si.
什么时候再和我睡觉?
睡什么觉 做就是了
拿来
谢谢
Gracias.
再见
Ciao.
快开 霍希・冈萨雷斯
Now,Jorge Gonzales.
我是法警
开车
好吧 我开
Okay.
你打算怎么做? 打算怎么做?
What are you gonna do? What are you gonna do?
尽我所能
What I do best.
所有涉及的人 所有得利的人
Anyone who was involved. Anybody who profited from it.
所有瞪眼看我的人 我要宰了他们
Anybody who opens their eyes at me, I'm gonna kill 'em.
噢 天啊
Oh, God!
能听见吗?
我头痛
我要开始提问了
假如你不如实全盘交代
你会知道什么叫惨不忍睹
我要剁了你的手指
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
若有必要 一根一根剁
这是止血用的
好了 开始
Okay? Ahora.
别来吓唬我
知道我是谁?
知道我是谁吗?
Huh? You know who I am?
拉曼达 的成员
拉曼达
对吗?
Correct?
对
Correct.
很好
Okay.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
- 我很熟悉这一套 - 是吗
你想知道什么?
你想知道什么 啊?
你想知道什么?!
拉莫斯 绑架案
在交货地点出什么事了?
- 出什么事? - 不知道
No se nada.
我们只是奉命绑走她
我们就做了这些
谁下的命令?
不知道
不知道?
不知道 不知道
不知道 不知道 我们分工在不同的组
嗓音 打电话来
我们负责抓人
然后再交给监管人
老板从不亲自出马
他们只负责谈交易
就这些
谁下的命令?
嗯?
Hmm?
我们叫他 嗓音
嗓音 好吧
嗓音
La Voice.
嗓音 怎么找到他?
不知道
不知道?
你肯定?
好吧
Okay.
相信你
谈谈监管人的情况
我是职业的
是
我是职业选手
我只做份内的事
谈谈监管人的情况
- 监管人 - 监管人 是的 监管人
不知道?
不知道
- 不知道? - 不知道
他在仍的 狂欢 舞厅看场
他的左脸有块胎记
我们叫他屠夫
好的
他属 拉曼达 吗?
是 拉曼达
行了 很好
Okay. Well.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
请给我支烟
Give me one cigarette, please.
- 行 - 好
- Si. - Okay.
好了
很好
好了 朋友 该送你去另一世界了
Okay, my friend. It's off to the next life for you.
我保证你不会形单影只
I guarantee you, you won't be lonely.
复仇就是进餐 最好是冷盘
Revenge is a meal best served cold.
狂欢舞厅 仍
告诉我这女孩的事
我不认识她
- 小女孩 - 不认识
- La nina. - No.
不认识? 走
No? Vamos.
是我
别开枪 别开枪
告诉我这女孩的事
认识她吗?
不认识?
No?
嗯?
Hmm?
我听你在讲西班牙语 你是美国人 是吧?
I heard you speaking Spanish. You're American, right?
- 你也是 - 是
- And so are you. - Yeah.
- 见鬼 哪来的? - 新泽西
- Get out of here. Where are you from? - I'm from NewJersey.
- 新泽西来的? - 是
- You from New Jersey? - Yeah.
我也是新泽西来的 听着
I'm from New Jersey. All right, listen to me.
告诉我是怎么运作的 全部过程 怎么运作的
一切都由一只手机操纵
All right. Everything is done up by cellphone.
我们只管等电话 号码屁都不知
You just wait around for calls, and we don't even have a fucking number.
谁付你钱?
Who pays you?
我们有张ATM卡 每两星期取200块钱
We got an A.T.M. card. We take out 200 fucking measly dollars every two weeks.
- 200块? - 是
- Two hundred dollars? - Yeah.
- PIN码是什么? - 什么?
- What's the PI N number? - The what?
PIN码 密码
The PI N number. Code number.
- 4747 - 4747
- 是 - 好 你没撒谎?
- Yeah. - Good. You wouldn't lie to me, right?
- 没 老兄 - 你杀了她?
- I'm not lying, man. - Did you kill her? You didn't kill her, did you?
没有
No.
别对我撒谎! 别对我撒谎! 是你杀了她?
Don't lie to me. Don't lie to me! Did you kill her?
老兄 你让我极度紧张
Oh, man, you're making me fucking nervous.
- 你杀了没有? - 没! 老板干的 或是他弟弟
- Did you kill her? - Noway. The fucking boss did, or his brother.
谁是老板?
- 我们从不见面 - 你没撒谎?
- We never see his face. - You're not lying to me, are you?
没 见鬼! 我说的是实话
No. Goddamn it! I'm telling you the truth!
告诉我你从没见过谁?
Tell me, who? You never see whose face?
我们在另一间房间
Well, we were in the otherroom
他对着小女孩大叫 他侄子被杀了
andhe wasyellin'at the girl 'cause his nephew got killed
钱也被偷走了
and the money got stolen.
等等 有人偷了什么钱?
Wait, wait. Wh- What? Somebody stole what money?
- 要交的赎金 - 谁偷的?
- The ransom money at the drop. - Who? Who stole it?
- 他说是贪污警察拿走的 - 谁?
- He said some fuckin' crooked cop took it. - Who?
- 范托斯 - 范托斯
- Fuentes. - Fuentes?
是 没错
Yeah, that's right.
还好吗? 嗯? 新泽西小子
All right? Huh?Jerseyboy?
现在好点
Yeah. Now.
- 这个叫范托斯的 - 是
- This Fuentes guy? - Yeah.
他是反绑组的头
He's a lieutenant for the Anti- Kidnapping Division.
范托斯 你干了什么?
Fuentes is. What'd you do?
- 噢 老兄 - 告诉我女孩的事 你干了什么?
- Oh, man. - Tell me about the girl. What'd you do?
- 你干了什么? - 我只是奉命行事
- Huh? What'dyou do? - I just do what they told me.
- 你只是奉命行事? - 是
- You do what they tell you to do? - Yeah.
你跟她道别了? 回答问题
Did you say good- bye to her? Answer my question.
- 你跟她道别了? - 没!
- Did you say good- bye to her? - No!
- 没有? 现在是机会 说再见 - 妈的!
- You didn't? Here's your chance. Say good- bye. - Oh, shit!
说再见 说再见
Say good- bye to her. Say good- bye to her.
妈的放我走!
Fucking let me go!
雷克?
Rico?
他们把那女孩往墙上扔
她动也不动
不动弹了
他们把她尸体放在车尾箱里
然后就开走了
谁? 他们是谁?
老板的弟弟
我认得出他的声音
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
现在听着
如果告诉我上哪能找到老板
我就放你条生路
但我不知道
真的不知道
- 不知道? - 不知道
- No? - No.
我会还你那女孩
什么女孩?
那女孩
你要那女孩吗?
是 但什么女孩? 你在说什么?
那女孩
在这里?
是
Si.
肯定?
是
Si.
带我去看
- 请讲 我是葛蕾诺 - 听着 是我
- Si, Guerrero. - Listen, it's me.
是我 是不是有个小女孩 最近被绑架了?
Yeah, it's me. You know anything about a young girl being kidnapped recently?
- 约12岁左右 - 是 就昨晚
- She's about 1 2 years old? - Yes, that's last night.
- 你有消息? - 她叫什么名字?
- Do you know something? - What's her name?
卡米拉 卡米拉・瓦伦西亚丝
Uh, Camilla. Camilla Valencias.
卡米拉? 是卡米拉吗?
?Camilla? ?Se llama Camilla?
- 是 - 我找到她了
- Si. - Okay. I got her.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
- 克雷塞 怎么回事? - 没事
- Creasy, what happened? - It's okay.
- 坐下 放松 - 卡米拉 没事吧?
Sit down. Relax.
她没事 你银行有人吗?
She's okay. She's okay. You got banking connections?
有 有人
Yes, I have connections.
密码4747
Okay. The PI N number's 47 47.
我想知道是谁把钱存入账号的
I wanna find out who's putting money in that account.
4747.
了解一个叫范托斯的警察吗?
What do you know about a cop named Fuentes?
反绑组的
He's with the Anti- Kidnapping Division.
是他开车带山默尔・拉莫斯 去交货地点的
He's the one who drove Samuel Ramos to the drop.
- 范托斯? - 是
- Fuentes? - Si.
- 她是谁? - 稍后问她 她会全盘说出
- Who is she? - You can ask herlater. She'll tellyou anything.
你对范托斯了解多少?
What do you know about him? About Fuentes?
三年前他们在他车后尾箱里 发现了五万美金和一具尸体
Three years ago they caught him with $50,000 and a dead body in the trunk ofhis car.
- 哼 - 未受指控
- Huh. - Never charged.
逮捕的警官作不了因为他死了
Arresting officer couldn't testify 'cause he was dead.
- 他属于 拉曼达? - 嗯
- Is he La Hermandad? - Mm- hmm.
- 知道他住哪里吗? - 住在法警大院
- You know where he lives? - He lives in a judicial compound.
行动时有一队车
He travels by motorcade.
克雷塞 他的重保护 比墨西哥总统还严密
Creasy, he's betterprotected than the president ofMexico.
他会需要保护的 你来照顾她?
He's gonna need it. You gonna take care of her?
- 是 怎么找你? - 我找你
- Yes. Well, how can I find you? - I'll find you.
联邦调查局 墨西哥城
这是我的管辖区
This is my jurisdiction.
我和克雷塞一样都想抓这个人
I want this man as much as Creasy does.
他一个周末伸张的正义 比法庭10年伸张得还多
He'll deliver more justice in a weekend than 10 years ofyour courts and tribunals.
- 离他远点 - 我是想
- Just stay out ofhis way. - I plan to.
若能办到 我还想帮他
I will even help him, if l can.
但是 我想先弄弄明白
But, uh, I would like to understand him.
说说吧
Give me that.
苹塔 拉莫斯
Pita Ramos
对你是个数字
that's a numberto you.
多一个死亡数字 但仅是数字
You know, one more dead, but a number.
她对克雷塞意味着什么?
What was she to Creasy then?
她让他重拾生活的意义
She showed him it was all right to live again.
但却被绑匪夺走了?
And the kidnappers took that away, huh?
他们会后悔动了她一毛一发
And they're gonna wish they never touched a hair on her head.
一个男人可成为一位艺术家
A man can be an artist
在任何东西上 食品 等等
in anything food, whatever.
这要看他对该物有多精通
It depends on how good he is at it.
克雷塞的艺术就是死亡
Creasy's art is death.
他即将描绘他的杰作
He's about to paint his masterpiece.
其它没什么好说的了
I don't have anything else to say.
我要这张卡的账户资料
密码是4747
是 有偿 服务
嘘 我不是来伤害你的
教堂里 他们说要学会宽恕
宽恕是他们与上帝的事
Forgiveness is between them and God.
我要做的就是让他们见面
It's my job to arrange the meeting.
别动 把手放下 放下
Don't move. Put your hands down. Put 'em down.
约翰 克雷塞先生
SenorJohn W. Creasy
因涉嫌枪杀两名法警而遭拘捕
is underarrest for the murder oftwo officers oftheJudicial Police.
并涉嫌卷入
He's suspected ofpossible involvement
涉嫌卷入露 苹塔 拉莫斯 绑架案
ofpossible involvement in the kidnapping ofLupita Ramos.
听得见吗?
Can you hear me? H uh?
知道在哪里吗?
Know where we are?
我们就在交易搞砸的桥下
We're under the bridge where the deal went bad.
赎金被人偷了 想说说是怎么回事吗?
The ransom got stolen. You wanna tell me what happened?
- 听说过 拉曼达 吗? - 是 听说过
- Haveyou heard of La Hermandad? - Yes, I have.
- 知道是什么组织吗? - 知道
- Do you know what it is? - Yes.
我就是 拉曼达 的老大
- 你是老大? - 是
- You're the president? - Yes.
老大? 哇
The president? Wow.
看着我
Look at me.
哦 你看不到 对不起
Oh, you can't. I'm sorry.
怎么样?
How's that?
让你看看这里有些什么
Let me show you what I got here.
看见这个了吗? 这是装料器 是罪犯用来藏钱和毒品的
See this? This is a charger. It's used by convicts to hide money and drugs.
他们把它放入身体 塞入直肠
They stick it in their body. They tuck it up their rectum.
觉得熟悉吗? 这个 看着
You familiarwith that? This Look at me.
笔式雷管
Pencil detonator.
定时器 用作接收和发送器
Timer, used as a receiver- transmitter.
C- 4 高爆破力
C- 4. Highly explosive.
把它们组合起来就是炸弹
You put 'em all together, you got a bomb.
不是很尖端 但威力强大
Not very sophisticated, but very powerful.
现在你屁眼里就塞着这个
That's whatyou have in your ass right now.
别动 别动 别动
Don't move. Don't move. Don't move.
廉价手表 带传呼功能
Cheap watch. Pagerwatch.
用来发送传呼到接收器 它现在就在你屁股里
Used to send a page to the receiver that's upyour behind right now.
那么 我这就发个传呼给你
So, I'm gonna send you a page
你会收到它
which you will receive
在5分钟之后
in five minutes.
现在
Now.
你还有5分钟可以告诉我 你手下和绑匪发生什么了
You got less than five minutes to tell me what went down between your men and the kidnapper.
我与绑匪无关
I have nothing to do with the kidnapper.
- 4:30 - 不 不认识他
- Four minutes and 30 seconds. - Nothing. I don't know him.
不认识? 4:25
You don't know? Fourminutes and 25 seconds.
4:20 肯定吗?
Four minutes and 20 seconds. Are you sure?
好吧
Okay.
我有的是时间 你没有 但我有
I got all the time in the world. You don't, but I do.
- 放松 放松 伙计 - 我很放松
- Hey, relax, relax, buddy. - I'm relaxed.
还有3:59
You got three minutes, 59 seconds.
我瞄见有机会 后来就得手了
I saw the opportunity, and I got lucky.
还有呢?
And?
我让我的人埋伏好 我们得到指示要去哪里
And I had my men ready as we got instructions where to go.
你让你的人准备好去偷赎金
You had your men ready to steal the drop.
你让你的人准备好杀个绑匪
You had your men readyto kill one of the kidnappers,yeah?
你干了好多次了
You've done this manytimes.
出什么事了 伙计?
- 绑匪头子的侄子就是一个 - 对 对 中彩了
- One of the nephews of the head kidnapper - Bingo. Bingo. Bingo.
- 是啊 你干了好多次了 - 很多次 是
- Bingo, yeah. You've done this many times, huh? - Many times, yeah.
- 还杀了很多受害人 不是吗? - 拜托 老兄
- Yeah. Killed many victims too, haven't you? - Come on, sir.
- 我们已尽力了 - 尽力去杀?
- We just make out as best we can. - "As best we could"?
2:47
Two minutes, 47 seconds.
等等 等等
Wait- Wait a minute. Come on.
- 我有份小礼物送你 - 送我?
- I have a little gift for you. - Forme?
- 是啊 是啊 - 是什么?
- Yeah. Come on. Come on. - What do you got?
根本没1000万 只有半袋钱
There was no $10 million. There was one halfin the bags.
赎金是1000万美金 分装在两个袋子里
The ransom was $10 million? They put it in two bags.
- 每袋500万 对吗? - 两袋没错
- Five million in each bag, right? - Two bags, true.
但其中一袋一半是白纸
But one has halfpaper
另一袋全是白纸
the other onlypaper.
也许是你的人偷的
Maybe your men stole it.
在交钱之前就被人调包了
Whoever did it took it before the exchange.
好吧 在拉莫斯家里
Okay. At the Ramos house
在交钱之前 谁把袋子放车上的?
before the exchange, who put the bags in the car?
- 猜是谁? - 谁?
- Guess what. - What?
拉莫斯的律师 乔丹 卡夫斯
Ramos lawyer,Jordan Kalfus.
- 乔丹 卡夫斯? - 是
- Jordan Kalfus? - Yeah.
佩德罗
Pedro.
先生 求你
Sir? Please.
很遗憾 对那女孩我深感遗憾
I- I'm sorry. I'm really sorry for the girl.
生意就是生意 你知道 我是职业的
It was just business. You know, I'm a professional.
每个人都这么说 我是职业的
That's what everybody keeps saying. "I'm just a professional."
都这么对我说 我是职业的 我是职业的
Everybody keeps saying that to me. "I'm just a professional. I'm just a professional."
我听够受够了 明白吗?
I'm getting sick and tired ofhearing that. You understand me?
你现在要干嘛?
What are you going to do now?
我要干嘛? 离开 我得走了
What am I gonna do? I'm gonna leave. I gotta go.
- 是 得走了 - 拜托 我怎么办?
- Yeah. I got - Come on. Come on. What about me, huh?
- 你怎么办? 你还有40秒 - 拜托
- What about you? You got 40 seconds. - Come on.
- 35秒 - 最后的愿望 求你了
- Thirty- five. - A last wish, please. Please.
最后的愿望? 我但愿你能有更多的时间
Last wish? I wish you had more time.
嘿! 嘿! 嘿!
Hey! Hey, hey!
乔丹 卡夫斯寓所
缺影印纸
对账单 乔丹 卡夫斯
山默尔・拉莫斯
海岸银行
喂
Hola.
- 玛丽安娜 是我 - 克雷塞 你在哪里?
- Mariana, it's me. - Creasy, where are you?
听着 我搞到些看似是 凯门岛海岸银行的银行密码
Listen, I got something that looks like banking codes from BankCoast in the Cayman Islands.
- 请帮我尽快解译出来 - 谁的账户?
- I need it translated as fast as you can. - Whose account is it?
乔丹 卡夫斯 好像有美金的存款和提款
Jordan Kalfus, andit looks like U.S. deposits and withdrawals.
再查一下 山默尔 拉莫斯 的账户
Give me the same thing on Samuel Ramos.
山默尔 拉莫斯 就这点?
Samuel Ramos. That's it?
- 就这点 - 好的
- That's it. - Okay.
这边请
谢谢
Gracias.
- 克雷塞 - 山默尔
- Creasy. - Samuel.
亲爱的?
Honey?
怎么了?
What's going on?
我也想知道 究竟怎么回事?
That's what I wanna know. What is going on?
嗯 山姆?
Huh, Sam?
问你太太几个问题 好吗?
I'm gonna ask your wife a couple of questions, okay?
你敢乱动
You move
不说真话
you make one sound
我就把你宰了 明白吗?
I'll snatch the life right outta you, you understand?
怎么回事 莉莎?
What happened, Lisa, hmm?
你也有份?
Were you in on this?
- 或者只有你先生 嗯? - 什么有份?
- Orwas it justyour husband, huh? - Am I in on what?
你知道我在说什么 苹塔 的绑架被害 你是否也有份?
You know what I'm talking about Pita's kidnapping, her death. Wereyou a part ofit?
- 苹塔 被害是因赎金被偷了 - 闭嘴!
- Pita got killed because the ransom got stolen. - Shut up!
是 钱被偷了 没错 他说得对
Yeah, the moneywas stolen. You're right. He's right.
钱被威特 范托斯偷了 偷走多少?
The moneywas stolen byVictor Fuentes. How much was stolen though, huh?
- 250万美金 对吧? - 你在说什么?
- $2.5 million, right? - What are you talking about?
他知道我在说什么 威特 就得了250万 不是吗?
He knows what I'm talking about. $2.5 million. That's whatVictor got, isn't it?
- 你们在说什么? - 250万
- What are you talking about? - 2.5 million.
250万给了你律师乔丹 卡夫斯
2.5 million to yourlawyer Jordan Kalfus
他存入了凯门岛的银行户头 可惜他无命享用
that he put in an account in the Cayman Islands, but he won't get a chance to spend it.
另外500万在哪里 山姆?
What happened to the other five, Sam?
250+250 1000万中的500万
Huh? That's 2.5, 2.5. What is five from 10?
很好 还有500万呢 山姆? 告诉你太太
That's five. What happened to the other five, Sam? Tell yourwife.
现在是你说话的机会 还有500万呢?
It's your chance to talk. What happened to the otherfive?
- 你有太太吗 克雷塞? - 不 我没有
- You got a wife, Creasy? - No, I don't have a wife.
那你就不会知道告诉你太太真相有多难
Then you'll never know how hard it could be to tell your wife the truth.
不 你有太太! 告诉我怎么回事!
No, you have a wife! You tell me what happened!
就在这房间 我父亲祈祷
It was in this room that my father prayed.
- 我不管你父亲的屁事! - 我父亲祈祷
- I don't give a fuck about your fucking father! - My father prayed.
他就在这房间祈祷他的赌债和背叛能得到宽恕
He prayed that his gambling debts and his infidelities would be forgiven right in this room.
- 山默尔! 我爱你! - 什么 莉莎?
- Sam uel! I love you! - What, Lisa?
- 告诉我真相 - 我没继承过王国! 这就是真相!
- Tell me the truth. - I didn't i nherit a ki ngdom! That's the truth!
你想知道真相? 我继承了他的赌债和烂摊子
You wanna know the truth? I inherited his debt and his mess.
- 继承了他的律师乔丹 - 告诉我我的宝宝怎么了!
- I inherited his lawyerJordan - You tell me what happened to my baby!
说! 说!
Say it! Say it! Say it!
说! 说! 王八蛋!
Say it! Say it! Be a fucking man!
乔丹告诉我她坐在房间里
Jordan told me she'd sit in a room
整天都在看卡通片
and watch cartoons all day
还有冰淇淋吃两天后就还给我们
and she'd eat ice cream and we'd have her back in two days.
他骗我!
He lied to me!
所以他得妈的去死! 我干的!
That's why he's fucking dead! I did it!
我干的 莉莎!
I did it, Lisa!
我同意了绑架
I agreed to the kidnapping.
我做是为了我们 为了我们三个
I did it for us for the three of us.
真抱歉 莉莎
I'm so sorry, Lisa.
杀了他
You kill him.
你不杀我杀
You kill him or I will.
你知道 他们都说
Huh. You know, they say a, um
子弹会说真话
a bullet always tells the truth.
从不说谎
It never lies.
这对我不适用 山默尔 也许
It didn't work for me, Samuel, but maybe
也许对你适用
maybe it'll work for you.
我会为你祈祷
I'll prayfor you.
这就是由ATM卡得知的住址
PIN密码帮了大忙
但却根本没有 嗓音 这个人
那是谁?
就是他
嗓音
我的人进入了屋子
以注射 霍乱 疫苗为借口
我们必须注射整个区
我们在屋子里装了窃听器 并偷走了他的照片
现在是时候去追捕他了
明天就让他的照片见报
谢谢
Gracias.
要想活命
就别登那些照片
- 喂 - 喂
- Hola? - Hola.
- 克雷塞先生? - 是 是我
- Mr. Creasy? - Yeah, it's me.
- 我帮你查了密码 有地址了 - 是吗?
- I traced the PIN for you and I have an address. - Yeah?
持卡人叫蕾娜・罗沙・桑切斯 嗓音的老婆
The cardholder is Reina Rosas Sanchez, the wife of"The Voice.
她住在洛斯・阿科斯区 阿匹亚大楼的26D室
She lives in Los Arcos, apartment 26D, Via Appia.
- 很好 - 还有一件事
- Good. - And another thing.
买份今天的报纸 上面有 嗓音 的照片
Pick up today's paper andyou'll have a picture of"The Voice.
很好 谢谢
Good. Thank you.
嘘 嘘
Shh, shh, shh.
他进去了 如何行动?
待命 待命
约瑟? 怎么了?
Jose? Que te pasa?
- 站住 站住 - 滚出去 兔崽子!
站住 站住!
出去 让孩子出去 快!
让孩子出去 出去!
快!
坐下
坐下!
蕾娜・罗沙 是吗?
是
Si.
好
Okay.
这是谁? 这是谁?
嗯?
Hmm?
是谁?
嗯?
Hmm?
是谁?
丹尼尔
丹尼尔什么?
丹尼尔 罗沙 桑切斯
嗓音?
是
Si.
好 他是他的弟弟?
- 是? - 是
- Si? - Si.
他叫什么?
阿雷欧
阿雷欧 罗沙 桑切斯 好
Aurelio Rosas Sanchez. Okay.
好
Okay.
你就是丹尼尔的老婆?
是
Si.
怎么联络他?
嗯?
Huh?
怎么联络他?
我们呼他
他用手机回电
打给他
这里没信号
必须得去屋顶
那就出去
出去
等一等 他们要接电话了
准备好追踪他
若幸运 我们就能抓住 嗓音
你好 丹尼尔
Hola, Daniel.
克雷塞先生
Senor Creasy.
是 你的家人在我这里
Yeah. Yeah, I got your family here.
你弟弟看来不太好
Yourbrother doesn't look too good.
蕾娜还有八个月的身孕吧?
Yeah, Reina, she's what, about eight months?
嗯? 你想谈判吗?
Huh? You wanna negotiate?
生命中家人最重要
The most important thing in life is family.
同意吗?
Do you agree?
同意
I agree.
现在我家人在你手上
And there you are. You have my family.
大部分的家人
Well, most of my family.
我太太和我分开了 你知道是怎样感受
My wife and I are separated. You knowhow that is.
现在认真地告诉我 你要多少钱?
Now, tell me seriously, h- how much do you want?
啊
Ah.
你弟弟要跟你说话 稍等
Your brotherwants to speak to you. Yeah, hold on.
你到底要干嘛?
听我说
听着 听着
我要把你家人一块一块地 给宰了 明白吗?
I'm gonna take your family apart piece by piece. You understand me?
一块一块地! 闭嘴!
Piece by piece. Shut up!
我不要你的钱!
I don't want your money!
你明白吗? 明白吗? 我要你!
Do you understand me? You understand me? I want you.
我在听
I'm listening.
我在听 丹尼尔 我在听
I'm listening, Daniel. I'm listening.
好吧 我跟你一命换一命
All right, I will give you a life for a life.
谁的命? 你在说什么?
Whose life? What are you talking about?
谁的命 丹尼尔? 我要你!
Whose life, Daniel? I want you.
我会以她的命来换你的命
并换回我的命
And in exchange, I will get my life back.
- 什么命? 谁的命? - 那女孩的 苹塔的命
- What life? Whose life? - The girl's. Pita's.
- 苹塔死了 - 克雷塞!
- Pita's dead. - Creasy!
我是个生意人 她死了就一钱不值 她还活着
I'm a businessman. A girl dead is worth nothing. She's alive.
好吧
All right.
我要活着的证据 听见吗?
I want proof of life. You hear me?
我要活着的证据 我要
I want proof of life. I want I want
我要她小熊的名字 她怎么叫她小熊的?
I want the name of her bear. What does she call her bear?
你让她告诉你
You tell herto tellyou
再告诉我她怎么叫她小熊的
to tell me what she calls her bear.
小朋友 你怎么叫你小熊的?
- 是 - 克雷塞
- Yeah? - Creasy.
她叫她的小熊克雷塞熊熊
She calls the bear Creasy Bear.
记住
我会以她的命
换你的命
还有我弟弟的命
好的
Okay.
O- Okay.
我还你弟弟 你还我女孩
I give you your brother, you give me the girl.
- 好吧 - 哪里?
- All right. - Where?
他离开了屋顶
失去信号 信号被切断
他去向不明 去向不明
该死
喂?
Hello?
莉莎 听着 别挂
Lisa, listen to me. Don't hang up.
我想苹塔还活着
I think Pita's alive.
我再也受不了打击了
I can't take this anymore.
走普巴拉公路
Take the road to Puebla.
从34号出口出去 等在南面
Get offjunction 34, south side.
两小时后那里见你
I'll meetyou there in two hours.
她在哪里?
So where is she?
就在那里 看见那两部车吗?
She's right over there. You see those two cars out there?
苹塔 是被 丹尼尔 绑架的
Pita's kidnapper, Daniel
这是他弟弟
this is his brother.
拿着
Here.
我上桥去接苹塔
I'm goin' up on the bridge to get Pita.
有什么三长两短 你对准他脑袋
Ifanythinggoes wrong, youput it to his head.
扣动扳机 好吗?
You pull the trigger, all right?
明白吗?
You understand?
不要
You don't
放了他直到苹塔和你在一起
Iet him loose until she's with you.
明白吗?
You got it?
不必等我了 明白吗?
And you don't wait for me, okay?
是
Yeah.
- 你会没事的 是吗? - 是
- You'll be all right. You okay? - Yeah.
克雷塞!
Creasy!
- 你没事吧? - 是
- You all right? - Yeah.
他们没伤害你吧?
They didn't hurt you?
嗨
Hi.
好了 你妈妈在等你 她就在桥底下
Your mother's waitin' for you. She's right down there at the end ofthe bridge.
- 好了 回家吧 - 好的
- Okay? You go home. - Okay.
- 好吧 - 你要去哪里?
- All right. - Where are you goin'?
我也回家
I'm goin' home too.
我要去兰海湾
I'm goin' to Blue Bayou.
噢 嘿
Oh, Hey.
我有东西送你
I got something for you.
最后一位数也有了
I got the last number too.
我爱你 克雷塞
I loveyou, Creasy.
你爱我吗?
And you love me, don'tyou?
是 我爱
Yes, I do.
真心的 苹塔 走吧
With all my heart. Pita, go.
- 去吧 跑 - 再见
- Go. Run. - Bye.
走
Vamos!
- 苹塔! 宝贝过来 没事了 - 妈妈!
- Pita! Baby, come here. It's okay. - Mom!
- 妈妈! - 快来! 好了 现在放你走
- Mom! - Come on! Okay, I'll let you go now.
妈妈!
Mom!
约翰 克雷塞 1956.1.4- 2003.12.16
嗓音 丹尼尔 桑切斯于03年 12月16日的拘捕行动中被击毙
特别鸣谢墨西哥城 一个非凡之地